[Music]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at
e-r. s radio is brought to you by the it
computer society and by It software
Magazine online at computer.org
[Music]
software hello everyone welcome to this
episode of software engineering radio
Our Guest today is Prine gar Prine is
director of product at LinkedIn he has
over decade of experience building
digital advertising products using Ai
and ml today the topic of our discussion
with Prine is in how geni has impacted
the development of digital attech
platforms welcome to this show Prine
it's great to have you here is there
anything else you'd like to add to your
bio before we jump right in yeah thank
you Kanan thanks for the opportunity
this is exciting to be here yeah nothing
more to add let's get started I'd just
like to point folks to two episodes that
we have done in the past one of them
episode 493 Ram Siri Hira on vectors and
machine learning it's a very related
topic the other one would be 610 Philip
Carter on observability for large
language model where some basics of gen
were covered so Kine what is a digital
attech platform great that's a great
question to start with let's take a step
back and understand what the world was
before digital advertising and then talk
about what digital advertising is and
what promises it made and what Solutions
it offers so before digital advertising
or Advent of Internet traditionally
advertisement was done on what we call
it traditional media is it print media
or linear Television right print media
may be on magazine or paper linear
television is basically a television
networks in the past so the three
challenges that that imposed number one
was reach to personalized audience was
very difficult on these mediums that
means you basically advertising for
pretty much most of the population and
selecting specific audience for your
interest was largely difficult number
two basically specific content or
customizing content for your audience
was even more challenging well you could
have different content in different
newspapers but it was still lot more
challenging than what Compares today
third basically and probably one of the
critical piece was understanding the
return on investment of the ADP was
extremely difficult especially when you
do brand campaigns or conversion
campaigns it was very difficult so with
digital advertising it promised to
address these three caps so that you can
actually reach to more granular and more
custom audiences solving the first
problem second you can have more
customized content to the audience when
they are active in the right channel as
well and last but not the least have
more fine grain attribution models or
measurement models that basically gave
you a lot more understanding about how
your ad spend is performing and what is
the return on investment on it so
digital advertise basically is a
centralized platform that basically
manages adds to who it is served when it
is served what content is served and
what channel it is served in and finally
measuring the performance of your ad
Spin and then optimizing continuously to
ensure that return on investment keeps
increasing as well in summary digital
advertising is a platform that manages
all these aspects can you describe what
was the State ofth art let's say five or
10 years ago yeah I think we talked
about like a 20 plus years back how
traditional media played a critical role
in advertisement with digital
advertising in the last 5 10 years lot
of the audience reach when do you reach
the audience and attribution models or
measurement models were rule based that
means you had less control on what kind
of audience you could actually reach
mainly demographic information like age
and gender for example and the number of
platforms basically they could reach was
also limited and as users adapted to
multiple platforms or multiple devices
digal advertising had to adapt as well
and last but not the least we had simple
measurement models that basically gave
you a decent understanding about what
your Roi was but with latest changes in
Ai and llms all of these things are
changing what does the current ecosystem
look like and who are the key
players yeah so if you see digital
advertising it's very complicated space
let's just break it down who the key
players are and what kind of a platforms
play a role here number one is
advertisers these are Big brands for
example or agencies who advertise on
behalf of the brands they are the people
who buy the advertisement that basically
get served on different surfaces or
channels in this case the second one is
Publishers these are the businesses that
provide the surfaces for digital
advertising that basically also includes
web pages or apps or any other such
Supply that provides dist advertising
spaces and connecting the buyer and the
publisher here are multiple ad platforms
let's just go through two or three such
ad platforms number one basically is
what we call audience exchanges these
are realtime buying platforms that
enable the buyers and sellers in this
case the advertisers and the Publishers
to provide their supply in the market
and also enable advertisers to buy the
digital advertising the programmatic
manner the second one is Audience
Network where basically if you're an
Advertiser you can use programmatic
access to buy on different partners
Publications that are available so one
of the example can be Google's own
Audience Network where you can actually
buy ads on Google and then it get
surfaced in various partner Publications
that they uh partner with and among all
these things are various other platforms
as well let's just talk about two things
which has cater to the needs of demand
and Supply so the demand side there are
demand side platforms that enable
advertisers to programmatically buy ads
on different ad exchanges as well as
audience networks as well so it's really
truly a Marketplace kind of a concept as
well on the flip side the supply side
platforms enables the Publishers to sell
their inventory so that multiple
advertisers can actually bid on that
inventory as well so it's quite a
complicated world with different
platforms as well but last let's just
focus on one thing which is to keep
these advertising business within a
trust and safe manner as well there are
verification companies that play a very
critical role so for example there will
be creative validators who will verify
whether the ad that's is being displayed
on the publisher caters to the need of
the policy that the publisher has
supplied or is it that of a good quality
to be shown on the publisher Network
itself so these are all different kind
of a partner platforms that play a very
critical role when it comes to
orchestrating and advertisement okay so
our topic today is how Jia has impacted
these platforms the development of these
platforms the teams that comprise these
platforms as well but why don't we start
with just explaining what geni is yeah I
think in a very simple term gen is a set
of AI stream that basically specializes
in generating content be it text audio
video or a multimodal Content has a
combination of all of these things why
is it important in digital advertising
is it because when a user consumes a
Content piece it's basically typically
in the format of text video or audio or
combination of all of these so making
sure that you generate the right content
to the Right audience at the right time
can be lot more scalably built and
dynamically built us think gen and gen
is not just about generation as well the
underlying models the llms that power
lot of the generi can also be used in
multiple purposes in digal advertising
the share of them understanding patterns
within the data and the Transformer
architecture both on the encoder decoder
side or decoder only models can be of
immense help to understand context
understand audience signals and then
really serve the most relevant and
customized ad to the Right audience at
the right time that's really where gen
both from a generation perspective and
also from a llm perspective is adding
value in digital advertising you
mentioned the Transformer architecture
why is that been so
key yeah that's a great question so
let's understand what a Transformer and
what self attention really means and how
that basically has transformed the
segmentation pieces as well as content
generation piece there is two things
that it really really help let's
understand what a Transformer model is
right I think the biggest change has
been the self attention that basically
gives you the contextual awareness of a
particular ad copy or a web page that
enables you to deliver contextual ad to
the Right audience as well the second
the large language models that basically
powers are built on Transformers are
able to understand and recognize
patterns in the data much better than
what it used to be because of parallel
processing lower computer capacity
compared to others and also amount of
data that they have been trained on as
well so Transformers one thing that is
really Excel set is pre-trained models
these are pre-trained models that can be
fine tuned to a specific industry as
well and can be argumented with more
data as well that's where like the RG
the rag models basically play a critical
role so again pre-trained models can be
fine-tuned and can be argumented as well
and in combination with the parallel
processing or the efficient use of Compu
capacity they're able to better segment
audiences and also better able to
generate content that are more relevant
to audiences so at the heart of it again
to summarize self attention parallel
processing of the data encoder and
decoder model that basically any Ables
them to parall process and generate
contextually aware data and pre-training
and fine-tuning of the through data
enables them to be more efficient in
segmenting the audiences as well as
reaching out the right as well as
creating the content for the audience
can we use an example to illustrate this
let's talk about take an example and
then talk about how the Transformer
architecture has really revolutionized
as well so let's use this use case
throughout our discussion so you are a
small tennis shop based out of San
Francisco and you're trying to basically
increase food traffic to your store so
there is more rackets and Tennis Goods
that are being sold so if that is
basically the SMB that you are and
that's your main objective then how can
advertising actually help so with that
context let's talk about how Transformer
architecture basically helps power some
of the capabilities so the Crux of what
Transformer architecture is self
attention right it's basically the AI
models understanding in a text or in a
video format like what is the most
relevant content and how they are
related to each other right giving
different weights and and relationship
to the different content that are
present in the sentence for example why
is it so important digital advertising
space is it provides you the context to
basically for the AI models to
understand the content that it's serving
the ad against and also to generate
human readable content that is more
relevant to the human ey as well that's
a main use case of Transformer models
within the digital advertising space so
for example if this tennis shop wants to
run ads and tailor message for different
audiences of different age and
demographic information what Transformer
architecture enables you to basically
generate those ad copy to different
segments with fully context of the brand
identity as well that is available and
that's the key thing that Transformer
architecture has enabled Raa in the
digital advertising space thanks Prine
for that intro let's get back a little
bit later drilling into the technologies
that impact the platform you brought up
the example of a small business owner a
tennis shop can we describe the Persona
of the users within this tennis shop
that will interact with the platform
yeah let me first start with the SMB and
then maybe expand a little bit because
there are so many different players that
play a role so typically in a stny shop
Let's assume that you are a so
proprietary owner who is running the sty
shop so you are a marketer you are the
owner of the shop you run the shop and
do everything and you have less time
less understanding about how digital
advertising actually works so you need
more sophisticated solutions that
simplifies the job for you so you are
the marketer in this case as well but
typically if you enlarge this use case
to larger brands or media agencies you
will have multiple personas in it it can
be a marketer who is basically running
ad campaigns on a day-to-day basis it
can be creative directors who are
primary responsible for generating
creatives or content that are used in
the digal advertising space or that are
used in the campaigns it can also be the
or marketing directors for end
responsible for managing multiple ad
campaigns and eventually responsible for
understanding the return on investment
as well and basically are responsible to
generate higher return on investment to
help them there will be analysts also
who basically do a lot more data work
that are necessary to basically
understand campaign setups campaign
optimization as well as understand the
return on investment as well so that
they can report up to these Executives
as well so there are multiple personas
that play a role and not to make this
more complex there are agencies that are
middle person in this as well where if
you are basically a bigger brand like
Coca-Cola you typically have agencies
you employed agencies to do the digital
marketing work they also run campaigns
on different objectives on behalf of the
brands so these are all some of the key
players in this particular space thanks
for that RI now in terms of the tennis
shop it's really a small business you
have multiple roles played by maybe the
same person the marketer the creative
director assuming that can we talk
through a day in the life of somebody
who's interacting with the platform and
you mention campaigns what exactly is a
campaign yeah let's start with the unit
campaign first and then maybe we can
expand on your question so in a very
simple term campaign basically is that
you add unit that you are actually using
to reach to your audience as well it can
be a set of combination between the
definition of the target audience that
you actually have and the creative or
the content that you're using to you
reach to this audience is basically
bundled in a campaign so you serve these
add content to your users then coming
back to your question on what does a
marketer a creative director or one
person all typically does or a day in a
job looks like right typically let's
divide into two set of things one is
campaign planning and second one is
campaign execution so what do we mean by
campaign planning right so in this case
the marketer of this particular shop has
to have a clear objective on what he or
she wants to achieve do they want to
basically generate awareness for the
shop increase footsteps to the shop or
want to do digital conversion from the
shop as well that means basically people
can visit the website and buy on the
website also there are multiple obes as
a market you may want to achieve so all
those things basically goes into
campaign planning in addition to that
who are my target audience understanding
of it doing research on that and what
kind of a budget I have in what to
allocate to different objectives and
what kind of content I can actually
create to reach out to these specific
audience all those things basically goes
into campaign planning the second part
of the job basically is campaign
management where you are incorporating
all the planning that you have done into
a marketing campaign which basically
means you are now setting up an audience
who you want to reach you are using the
creatives to serve to those audiences
and you are continuously measuring the
performance of your ad campaigns or
marketing campaigns and then optimizing
or fine-tuning your campaign operations
so that you continue to to achieve your
objective better and better and of
course this is easy to say than done
because this is a complex domain needs a
thorough understanding about like how to
optimize different levers that are
present to get the maximum return on
investment this is really where AI
automation may be very very helpful for
specifically for these SM smps imagine a
platform an ad platform who can automate
using AI the complete operations and
simplify it to a single click operation
can deliver a lot more value to the
these SMB owners and simplify the job of
them so that they can focus on their
core job which is running the shop in
this case and engaging with the
customers so that's really where AI
comes into picture to simplify all these
operations and ensure that you receive
the maximum Roi for the adment that you
actually do as the marketing director of
the small business how do I really
specify to the platform who my intended
audience is typically as I said in the
planning phase you need to basically
understand who your target audience are
it starts with an objective then you
determine let's just simplify this I
want to reach to audience of 20 to 40
years who live in San Francisco Bay Area
because I don't have a website to sell
my goods on so I need to convert food
traffic to my shop so if that is the
criteria then you basically use the
platform provides different levers it
can be reaching based on the Age based
on the occupation based on buyer intent
for example all those lever can be used
to set these are the type of audience
are most likely to come to my shop and
those are the audience I have to reach
to generate awareness and also create
food traffic to my shop as well so the
platform provides those capabilities in
the tools to make sure that you select
the desired audience you actually want
and now as a shop owner you may not know
these audiences and this is where the AI
powered predictive audiences come into
picture which basically are AI models
that basically understands typical
behavior of audiences for your business
what the buyer intention is is what kind
of signals they do rest of the internet
and then basically even use your own
specific sales data to recommend what
type of audience you should basically
reach as well that's what we call
predictive audiences and AI is basically
simplifies that planning and reaching
for a job as well for these SMP owners
that's a good Segway so in the next
several minutes I'd like to now drill
down into what the platform needs to do
and you mentioned it starts with the
model so can you explain what is the
approach of selecting different model
architectures for the platform if you're
an ad platform I think you're trying to
basically optimize across multiple
things as well one is what is the
context what is the object that the
advertiser actually want to reach and
based on that object you want to
basically make sure that the right
models are serving those platforms as
well that's one and what kind of a data
that we basically have so when it comes
to an ad campaign if near a platform and
you're thinking about model selections
right it's the platform data that is
also important which is the first party
data there is also importance of third
party data that basically means data
source from third party sources as well
but also what is really important is the
brand specific data as well so what do
you mean by brand specific data right so
maybe this is not that appropriate for
the SMB space or the small business that
in shop here but if you're basically
coca-colas of the world you have run
campaigns for multiple years with the
platform and you have very specific data
about what are the specific audience is
what kind of a conversion they basically
do and these data tells you a lot more
about what kind of performance we can
deliver on this so if you're basically
selecting a model and the model
selection basically depends upon this
data as well then the job at hand for
the platform as well so you want to
basically optimize for a couple of
things right one the performance of the
models that includes basically accuracy
and latency then the computational
resources that are actually required
from the model perspective as well
because you don't want to use large
language models or models that take
significant comp capacity for smaller
jobs like for example copy generation so
job specific tasks that are basically
needed as well and there's a significant
ask of transparency to the users as well
that's play a critical role in selection
of what type of models that are
necessary because certain aspects need
more transparency to the user like for
example copy generation or return on
investment measurement or measurement
piece whereas ad serving piece may not
need the same level of transparency for
the user so all these factors go into
the analysis of what different mod model
basically power different stages of
campaign management from a platform
perspective one of the things that I got
from what you said was that in the case
of audience segmentation you probably
need a large model but for copy
generation you need a small model or you
can live with the small model that's
more performing yeah that's a trade up
that platform can definitely do and
there these smaller models basically are
trained on like of much fewer parameters
than a large language model they take
this comp computational capacity from a
performance perspective you're
generating ad copies they are very
similar from a performance perspective
so that's a very valid tradeoff for this
particular use case do you have an
example of a small language model for
this space yeah I think Microsoft 53
basically can be a really good example
for search in fact like we were writing
a paper on this and how slms versus llms
can do better in terms of AD copy
generation and can do so on device we
were able to run some of these open
source models on our laptops to
basically generate ad copies so what we
did basically is the data set that was
used is Amazon's product catalog and
with little bit of a prompt engineering
we were able to run these models on
laptop and generate more very relevant
ad copy content that compares to what an
llms would actually do that were run on
AWS for example so yeah there are
multiple such slms that are also open
sourced that can actually help you
achieve some of these objectives coming
back to some other Concepts you had
mentioned earlier one was the encoder
and decoder can you explain that
relevance of that in this context sure I
think what makes a Transformer model
unique compared to rnns the traditional
rnns that we basically used to use is
the encoder and decoder architecture
right the encoder basically helps you to
understand map the relationship of
certain words from a contextual manner
so for example if you're actually
feeding a web page the coder model goes
through the web page and generates a
vector mapping of all the words listed
in the web pages and contextually ties
them together as well and if you're
asking the llms to basically generate an
art copy from the web page then the
decoder it plays a role which basically
then generates the necessary ad copy
based on the contextual mapping that the
encoder actually has done and in a
digitaling space this is even more
important because we talked about the
latency right you can do these things
more parallel so that we can still
maintain lesser latency and be within
the tolerance needed to serve an ad
platform on a publisher Network or own
and operated Network you introduced RNN
or recurrent neural network I'd like to
provide this link to our listeners on an
episode we have done earlier on neural
networks this is software engineering
radio episode 594 Sean morar on deep
learning with Elixir and Exxon back to
the encoder decod
architecture Prine can you take an
example of our SMB and contrast these
models and explain which one is used
where yeah definitely I think let's take
the same example of the 10 sha and try
to see how encoder decoder model or
decoder only model can be helpful so you
basically if you're at any shop your
campaigns are maybe set up in two
different ways number one basically for
audiences from 20 to 30 years old we
have copy generation and from 30 to 40
and 40 to 50 you have certain way of
copy generation let's just say that's
the use case and to make it a little bit
more complicated now you have English
speaking population and Spanish speaking
population you want to generate content
for both of the needs as well so this is
where the encoder decoder model and
decoder only model can be a lot more
useful so you have only one content that
you're uploading to the ads platform and
using that content all these different
variants are generated so to generate
English only models for different age
demographic decoder model is enough
because these are basically generated
through the prompts that are basically
providing and the initial copy version
that is being generated right whereas
you want to use the same initial copy
version to translate that into Spanish
version as well be contextually aware
human readable that's where encod and
decoder architect comes into picture so
a platform using different models can
actually serve all these multiple
variants that the SMB owner wants to do
as well what about the data that the
models are trained on they certainly
have to serve a very large variety of
advertisers Yeah so basically these
models get trained pretty much every few
hours in a day from vast amount of data
that is basically the first party and
third party data that the platform
actually owns and when you have to do
specialized operations for example
dynamically generate a content for an
Advertiser then you can also rely on a
retrial argumented generation mechanism
as well to generate brand specific
copies as well but you can imagine the
data that is basically used for this
right number one is any kind of a
product analytic that happen if you're a
social media platform that also support
advertisement any engagement that
happens on your platform that may be
clicks likes or any kind of a shout out
that actually happens that basically
tells you user Behavior that's very
critical data that goes in user intent
that means basically you have to
visualize a user journey in a funnel of
a buyer funnel basically that means let
just simplifying three stages first you
are trying to be aware of what you want
to purchase then you know basically that
find you more in the awareness stage
second basically you have narrow down on
paramet on certain key things and narrow
down on the products that you want to
purchase as well then you are more
deeper in research as well and third one
is basically conversion so a lot of
these engagement data from both first
party third party and even brand
specific conversion data gives signals
to the platform on where the user is in
the buyer funnel and this is completely
different for a b2c brand versus a b2c
B2B brand because the users and their
buyer funel are completely different so
that's a very critical data as well and
finally basically the ad the placement
of the ad where the ad is actually
served the context in that and how user
is engaging with that particular content
is also very critical and these are all
the data that basically is used by the
ad platform to power various
capabilities including audience
segmentation content generation ad
suring and measurement as well before I
forget I think lot of basically what the
trend also is the brands basically
providing lot of their sales data as
well to further understand conversion
and better understand the return on
investment that they are actually doing
as well that basically helps even the
ads platform to provide a lot more
granular information both online
conversion and offline conversion so in
this case what we mean by offline
conversion right someone engageed with
this tenis shops add but went to the
store and bought the tennis racket there
and that conversion that me they are
using a QuickBooks or anything or a CRM
solution that plugged into the ads
platform provides additional signal for
measurement as well so my take away from
that was that there's a lot of data that
is owned by the ad platforms but also as
a business owner I let the ad platforms
then accumulate signals from my website
website as well as like your CRM or
sales data or conversion data as well
right the more data these smbs or any
other brands can provide the better AI
models can be trained on for specific
needs specifically your conversion data
right like either in CRM or any other
data can be used in two purposes one in
measurement to better understand the ROI
the second pce is optimization now you
understand who are converting then you
can actually optimize and your
predictive audiences can be even more
better than before your ad serving can
be better as well because now you
understand what type of conversion is
happening on your platform is there a
privacy concern there with me as a
business Ander sharing all this with the
platform that's a very good question one
of the biggest blocker for uh any SMB or
a brand is the privacy or compliance
reasons right the bigger Brands you are
you have to go through various
compliance checks to ensure that the
right data is Shar right level of
masking is done or anonymity is done on
the data so the good thing basically
here and this is probably a very common
misunderstanding the ad platforms don't
really need specific user data or a pii
what we call right personally identified
information it needs aggregated data and
it's signed conversion data that's
basically what I realiz a lot more on
working with the brands making sure that
either through Solutions like capy which
is basically conversion apis are
injecting CRM data directly into the
clean room the ads platforms is a very
viable way to be both compliant and also
ensure that you provide the necessary
information for the platform to not only
measure the effectiveness of your ad
campaign but also optimize for them for
future needs you mentioned an acronym
cppy can you explain what that cppy is a
conversion API it's basically server to
server signal that is being sent so for
example if a conversion actually happen
in this case the 10is Shop's website
basically send sends conversion signal
directly to the ad platform in terms of
model in this extra signals that are
sent over to the model does that fall
under fine tuning or is that a
completely different way to think about
fine tuning it definitely is part of
fine tuning as well because the more
conversion data basically has the
measurement model that can be
attribution models get additional
signals for you to ensure that can
provide more information the fine tuning
also is parameter tuning right it's
basically narrowing down the parameters
to the most relevant parameter that are
necessary pruning of the parameters and
also pie piece of it as well and the
second piece of fine tuning also is
relying on reinforcement learning either
human or AI base to ensure that you
weigh the parameters clear clearly as
well so yeah fine tuning typically
refers to that but you can call this as
fine tuning because it enables your
models to be lot more accurate and here
reinforcement learning is by the
experience that the advertiser now has
in the ad campaign on how people react
to yeah so I think the platforms are
capable to basically get a reinforcement
learning through The Advertiser directly
as well based on the specific
questionnaire for example as well we can
also get feedback directly from the user
uh we run market research surveys that
provides very valuable signals from
there and also there are AI models that
basically does reinforcement learning in
this case to ensure that you continue to
learn and improve the performance of the
model you also had talked about rag or
retrieval augmented generation can you
contrast that with fine tuning so what
does a rag Ral argumented generation is
right so let's take basically the case
of the tennis shop an as platform May
understand an aggregated information
about tennis shops across the globe or
across United States but what is your
brand specializes in what is your brand
identity is something that the AI may
not be specifically aware of as well the
retrial argumented generation is a
technique where you basically Infuse
this brand specific data to your AI
models at the time of decision making to
ensure that you actually argument the
capability of the models to produce more
brand relevant data or brand relevant
content that means basically if you have
two St shops one is specializes in
tennis shop only and takes pride in it
on tennis gear only and the second one
basically specializes in tennis gear and
pickle ball you want to make sure that
the shop that you're advertising with is
takes pride in only tennish only shop to
make sure that the ad compy copy
generated is very specific to that I
know it just sounds strange I think
tennis lovers will understand the
difference between pickle ball and
tennis but yeah I think that level of
brand specificity is what rag really
enables right whereas fine tuning
basically are reinforcement learning is
basically an ability to for models to
continuously learn and improve on top of
it it may or may not have spec any
information about the brand specific
information and this fine tuning can be
done at the aggregated level that means
at the all the tennis shops together all
the sports shops together as well and
that's where the these are different in
nature so how is rack set up just
continuing on an example what do I need
as a tennis shop owner to provide to the
platform so that it can leverage my
specific data at runtime and not make
sure that the model is changed in any
form of fashion yeah let's first talk
about three critical components in Rag
and then tie it up to the T shop as well
so what is three things that are very
necessary right one is basically a
knowledge base of the brand these can be
graphs that are built to store this are
vector spaces as well that basically
analy said these are typically derived
from web pages any other brand specific
information that the T shop can actually
provide as well the second one basically
is the retrieval models how specifically
and what specific entity can you
actually retrieve to argument the data
uh to the main model that's the second
piece that are necessary and then
basically any kind of a reinforcement
running that you can actually run that's
the third piece of it but the main two
piece are basically the knowledge base
as well as the retrial model so if
you're basically a ten shop I think to
really help brand identity there are two
things that you can do really well one
is basically provide all your assets
that you actually have that may be web
pages that may be product cataloges
browers or any other thing any kind of a
sales that you basically run or
conversion that you happens on your
platform those are very specific to your
brand very specific to your own identity
that basically will help quite a bit
this is not something that you have to
explicitly do because if you have
history of campaigns that you have
actually run the platforms will actually
have access to those campaigns and from
that they can actually build better
repository for for your brand and also
ensure that the retrial model can
actually fetch the right data to
argument for the main models as well
just confirming that this is something
that the adart platform will maintain
per client so the argumentation is per
client let's just say right basically
the rag model is a generic framework
when a brand specific ad is in question
then the retrieval is basically very
brand specific so now let's get back to
how exactly the technology is behind
Genia I have made a lot of this better
so you did talk about vectors in rag can
you give an example or maybe explain
more what Vector embeddings are and I
did Point folks earlier to an episode
that we have done on that in the past
but a little bit of recap of that would
be useful one are vector embeddings
right so let's start there are three
concepts where may be important here one
is embeddings one is vectors and then
basically our Vector search and then
Vector space right so let's take the
same ten shop example and try to combine
everything together so embeding in a
very simple term basically is the
content that you actually have provided
to the platform right either webell
thing is basically converted into
vectors it's basically number okay and
they are converted in such a way that
basically you understand the context and
the relevancy or correlation between the
contents as well so that's where context
awareness really comes into picture the
second basically is Vector search as
well right so this is happens in a
vector space so let's take an example
Vector space is like a multi-dimensional
Vector space where all the assets and
the ad units and everything is basically
converted into embeddings and basically
store and the vector search is basically
identifying the right content the ad
unit to retrieve when a particular page
is basically shown to a user to Surface
ads on so let's take an example so you
are a tenis shop and you're basically
running ads on what you generally call
Audience Network right Audience Network
can be a publisher Network which is if
you are like Instagram or Facebook or
LinkedIn or Google you have ties with
the publishing Partners like CNN.com Fox
News Tennis Warehouse and many other
Publishers who sell their ad space for
these platforms so if a user basically
is let's just say for Simplicity here
browsing on CNN.com and PR is an a
tennis player so what happens here so
number one like uh these ad platforms
could have have two types like they
would have already had embeddings for
cnn.com various Pages they routinely
scan some of the publishing Network
convert them into embeddings and
basically build their Vector space based
out of it so that's basically the web
page content that is stored as embedded
in the vector space then you have this
tennis shop the San Francisco based
tennis shop they have multiple ad units
or campaign contents right that are also
converted into embeddings and this are
in the same space now the magic of
basically cating these things together
happens right when I visit the tennis
shop my behavior my buyer intention is
basically understood then from the VOR
embeddings in the vector space you now
know what is the content of the website
that you visiting as well and then the
ad platform then makes a selection of
what is the right ad you need to pick
for this particular content for this
particular user to serve it on it that's
how the embeddings vector sech and
Vector space basically combined together
to serve the most relevant content to
the user here that's me when I'm
visiting CNN.com so this is you when you
visited CNN.com we understand how Vector
search Vector embedding has come into
the picture what is the magic that
happens when this tennis shop really
wants to create an audience segment and
how are you chosen in there how does
that happen yeah that's a great question
right I like the way you used to ask the
questions on what used to happen 5 years
back and what has happened today right
let's take the same lens and try to walk
through this like 5 10 years back they
were mostly rule based segmentation
right so you used to basically identify
what is the key demographics that you
want to reach maybe age gender locations
so many different things but now
basically the AI models powered
predictive audiences is a lot more
popular so what do they basically
understand they definitely take
demographic information in addition to
that phography information that's
basically your professional data that
can be useful your behavioral data what
kind of a Content you engage with what
are the kind of contents that you don't
engage with that is important as well
what is your intent like at this time
what is your main objective basically
right that's the signal that you
actually get as well and all these
things basically getting fit into the
predictive on audience models to ensure
that you create the Right audience that
have higher propensity of engaging and
converting with your ad and that's what
basically predictive audiences is so
this is uh in the old time basically
there used to be lookalike audiences so
what do we mean by right right if the
most of your audience are 20 to 30 year
old in San Francisco or engaging with
that localize audience with expand that
audience base a little bit but
predictive audiences is lot different
than that right it's not just an
expansion of an audience but really a
deeper understanding about who uh what
kind of an audience have higher
propensity of conversion or meeting your
objective that's the key piece that
predictive audien is basically solve for
and Transformers have helped with that
you mention the attention mechanism is
that for predictive audience selection
or for generation of cont so I think the
Transformer architecture play a lot more
role on the generation of the content
but basically like if you're using an
encoding and decoding model models right
the context awareness really comes from
the encoding model and the generation
comes from the decoding model and they
actually help to generate the right
content for the audiences now you from
the encoder model you understand what a
web page they are actually engaged with
what is the context of the web page and
who the audience basically is and then
the decoder model plays a role of
generating the human readable content
whether it's text video or audio format
thanks rine so we covered the content
generation where you mentioned that the
Transformer architecture and
specifically the attention mechanism are
key I'll put a link and show notes to an
explanat video for the intention
mechanism that you pointed me to we also
then talked about predictive audience
targeting where the extensive data sets
that the model is trained on is what
enables this
capability and then lastly you started
to talk about content which is not just
text but audio and video let's not talk
about some of the multimodel
capabilities and how they relate to the
model and model selection because the
content that is generated is not just
text it's images and videos Etc so how
has that helped yeah I think multimodel
model clearly is the future from a
perspective that it provides lot more
personalized content Which is higher
performance content as well so
differentiate to take a step back like
typically a lot of the model used to
turn on different text speech and video
data right audio video and this thing
and then they used to combine together
again to make sure that the model
understands from a multimodality
perspective as well but like as you can
imagine there's lot more processing that
you have to do from having different
data sets strained and then basically
combining them together as well the
multimodal model approach really is
training with the native content that
has all three embedded in it right like
it's basically video with transcription
that has audio text as well as uh video
as well so training the models from in a
native way from a multimodal Content
itself they Trend to perform much higher
from a performance perspective as well
and because of higher performance
basically they can actually generate
content that are multimodal in nature
also that are a lot more native to the
that more a lot more performing to the
the end user as well one thing does come
to mind especially maybe for ad serving
because now this is realtime ad serving
it is taking a lot more into account of
your current behavior as your
interacting with the website can you
talk a little bit about performance how
has performance maybe improved or what
kind of role that pays in making sure
that the ad content is generated to your
current behavior and interactions yeah
so I think as I T talked about these are
models basically get retrained pretty
much every few hours right and if it's
basically your ad serving models those
are basically getting trained or your
predict to audience models those are
basically getting retrained every few
hours as well and while the campaign is
basically live your audience definition
may be changing because of predictive
audiences so for example I there are
signals that I actually have already
bought a racket and I'm out of the
market for racket purchase and I won't
be available in your audience
segmentation uh that is defined through
productive audiences so like the signals
that basically are live are as the
models are retrained are 5$ a long basis
as well these signals basically get
accounted for and your predictive
audence is very Dynamic from that
perspective bra I'd like to now get into
some of the team composition and how
that has changed with Genai is there
anything else you'd like to cover in the
current topic of capabilities before we
go there no I think from a technical
capabilities model capabilities I think
we covered really a good breath
definitely we can talk about how Team
Dynamics or organization structure play
a very critical role to execute on this
now let's talk about the teams how has
that change what does a cross functional
product team look like today in building
these platforms let's take the same
example of five years back how we used
to work and how we are working now or
how what direction we are moving in so
typically you might have seen in many
organizations as well there used to be a
separate AI team separate data science
team and there used to be product teams
which is typically made of product
managers backend front end engineers and
full stack Engineers that was the
typical composition of money
organizations as well we used to invest
quite a bit in AI capabilities the AI
team centrally used to optimize for
different businesses if you specifically
have different businesses within a large
organization what we realize from that
model is uh there is constant
prioritization is a big challenge in
this kind of a working environment
because specifically take example
LinkedIn has multiple business units and
they have different needs so managing
across all these things are very
difficult for a centralized AI team so
that's a challenge so the Second
Challenge also basically is the AI teams
are not so very closer to the product by
itself sometimes right and that
basically may be a challenge or they are
brought in much later in the product
development life cycle without the full
context of understanding about the
product they may not be able to come up
with the right solution to power the
products as well these are all the
challenges that basically used to occur
in this kind of a distributed model so
the new model that many of the
organizations are working towards are
already on right now is a more embedded
model within the product teams itself so
now the product team no longer has only
the back and frontend engineers and the
product manager they have the a
engineers and data scientists working
all together towards a single okr or
objective and key results right they
have single goals they are involved in
the product development right from day
one so they are part of the life cycle
fully they understand and they are
specialized in this particular product
areas as well this model helps to solve
a lot of those problems and where really
like the AI Engineers can actually build
solution that are a lot more tailor made
for the product capabilities there is a
second benefit also from this right now
you're are actually increasing AI
proficiency overall a proficiency within
the team so you're basically cross
educating the what traditional back and
front end Engineers where on AI
capabilities as well and they are not
more AI proficient and this really helps
to basically build like an AI first
model or AI first products those are
some of the key organization changes
that we are actually seeing to really
move towards the direction of AI
integrated or AI first products to
really completely use the power of AI to
add value to the products can you
comment on the overlap between between
an AI engineer and a data scientist sure
let's take maybe there are three
categories that typically we see in the
organization so there are data Engineers
or business analyst they basically may
be specialized in building data
pipelines building metrix dashboards and
other capabilities those are one type of
Engineers who work on data the second
one basically are like a product analyst
for lack of better term these are data
scientists also called Data scientists
who really work with the product teams
to understand opportunities in the
product so for example if you uh in the
onboarding flow of any kind of a product
there may be a lot of leakage that is
actually happening so identify the
points of leakage and identify and come
up with Solutions on how to prevent that
leakage to make sure that onboarding has
higher conversion all these work
basically is done through data these
kind of a second tier data scientists
like who basically work on these
capabilities and last but not the least
are the engineers who basically build AI
models or basically take the
foundational AI models and and convert
them or fine tune them for their own
specific needs or even build some AI
model that are serving custom purposes
as well so these are broadly three
categories one basically data Pipeline
and analytics second one is basically
product understanding product analytics
product recommendations third one
basically is model development and model
fine-tuning you did also mention that
more and more the expectation is that
the full stack Engineers are also
understanding and cognizant of what
these AI engineering tasks are too yeah
100% and I think what organizations are
looking is the product team that is as
lot more AI proficient even if they
basically may not be building the AI
model they are proficient in a way to
basically train an AI model do prompt
engineering if needed as well and use
the AI model the right way all those
capabilities are something that is
desired and also if you are basically an
engineer AI is here to stay it is in
your best interest in your professional
best interest to be AI proficient as
well learn the you know workings of AI
and enable the team to be successful I
think from that perspective as well it's
a very critical piece for what
traditionally like the full stack
Engineers used to be thanks rine
starting to wrap up now you talked a lot
about how gen has impacted the platform
how about how has digital attech adapted
to have ads show up at in the right form
or fashion now that we have more and
more conversational AI systems like chat
GPT and voice based platform in addition
to search based
yeah that's a great question I recently
wrote an article about this let's take
an example here also and this time we
are moving away from the tennis shop
example I think if anything the short
form videos are hugely popular now it
can be Tik Tok res Instagram Tik Tok I
don't know what it's called even on Tik
Tok Instagram reals for example a short
video right they designed in a way to
have shorter attention span for the user
right 60 seconds at Max basically so
this introduces a lot of challenges for
advertisers to advertise on this
platform but users are mostly engaged on
these kind of a medium right now so how
do you reach to these medium that are
basically primarily designed for lesser
attention span whereas if you're an
Advertiser you want the user to pay
attention to your ad engage with your ad
and convert with your ad as well right
and these kind of a thing is very
important for a marketer and from that
perspective a generative IR is really
useful how can a marketer or an
Advertiser really grab attention of a
user in a short form video format is
through interact ads or conversation ads
right basically giving an option for the
user to choose different kind of a
product they want to basically see
giving a survey questions or ask a
question and how to basically kind of a
provide a game or anything that within
the ads itself that they can engage with
as well so that's one of the way that
they actually they can engage with the
user in the short video format medium
and that's where generative AI can be
really useful because now depending upon
the user inputs the ads can actually
react with different messages that
actually follows up and when you want to
do this at scale generative ey can be
the that engine that can actually power
different variants of messages depending
upon the user choices I'll put in a link
to the article you mentioned in the show
notes along with the couple of the other
pointers you had for example on
Microsoft 53 would you have a similar
idea about ads that show up or the form
factor in which they show up when I'm
maybe I'm just chatting with chat GPT
what do I expect to see there yeah so if
you're basically
perplexity right which is basically
literally like a question in engine
their monetization model in the future
can be ads model so if you are basically
now asking about how does a tennis
racket work or what is the balance in a
tennis racket then they can basically
start showing ads and that ad can be
more conversational as well trying to
basically help the user narrow down on
what is the specific racket that can be
a lot more useful for his or her own
playing style right I think that's
really where the conversational AI ads
can be supered useful this is a great
conversation Prine where can people
contact you I think LinkedIn would be
the best place to reach out to me so I'm
happy to connect there and also answer
any questions further thank you so much
for coming on and it's wonderful
conversation thanks for having me K it
was great talking to you
here thanks for listening to SC radio an
educational program brought to you by It
software magazine for more about the
podcast including other episodes visit
our website at se-
radio.net to provide feedback you can
comment on each episode on the website
or reach us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter
or through our slack Channel at
seo. slack.com you can also email us at
team
e-r. this and all other episodes of SE
radio is licensed under creative comons
license
2.5 thanks for listening